Admissions Office Records 1940-1980
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Admissions Office Records
1940-1980
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 122
approximate 2290 items 1.5 linear feet 2 containers
Includes correspondence, memos, reports, fliers, projects, statistics, workshop information, minutes and newsletters.
Committees, 1948-1956, includes the records of the Coordinating Committee on Academic Relations, although other records on junior college policy and state coordination are included. Correspondence, memos, and reports make up the bulk of the material.
Conferences, 1962-1972, contains records from conferences of junior and community college personnel and faculty on the WSU campus on a wide variety of academic/professional subjects. Evaluations from participants make up the bulk of the subseries; other materials include correspondence, reports, memos, flyers.
The subseries Education, 1940-1980, consists of correspondence, studies, projects and statistics concerning all facets of education. A newsletter is also included.
Junior and Community Colleges, 1954-1977, consists of reports, studies, workshop information, minutes, flyer materials, and correspondence.
The records of the Admissions Office have been arranged in a single series, Alphabetical Subject File, 1940-1980. In order to retain as much of the original filing system as possible, the series has been divided into four subseries (the original Office of Admissions groupings) under headings created by the processor: Committees, 1948-1956; Conferences, 1962-1972; Education, 1940-1980; and Junior and Community Colleges, 1954-1977. The folders within each subseries have been placed in alphabetical order by subject.
The Collection is open for research use.
The records of the Admissions Office were transferred to the University Archives, Washington State University Libraries, by the Admissions Office in accordance with the approve records schedule in August 1982 (UA 82-21).
Washington State University. Office of Admissions--Archives; State College of Washington. Office of Admissions.; State College of Washington. Coordinating Committee on Academic Relations.; Washington Association of Community Colleges--Archives; Washington State University. Office of Admissions--Records and correspondence; Washington State University--Admission--Archives; Washington State University--Curricula--Archives
Community colleges--Washington (State)--Research--Archives; Universities and colleges--Admission--Research--Archives
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- Alphabetical Subject File, 1940-1980; I
  - Committees, 1948-1956; a.
    Includes the records of the Coordinating Committee on Academic Relations, although other records on junior college policy and state coordination are included. Correspondence, memos, and reports make up the bulk of the material.
    - Coordinating Committee on Academic Relations, 1948-1953; 205 items (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
    - Junior College Policy, 1950; 75 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - State Coordination, 1956; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, 1962-1972; b.
    Contains records from conferences of junior and community college personnel and faculty on the WSU campus on a wide variety of academic/professional subjects. Evaluations from participants make up the bulk of the subseries; other materials include correspondence, reports, memos, flyers.
    - Communications-History-Political Science, 1966; 65 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - English, 1962; 30 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Anthropology-Sociology-Preveterinary Medicine, 1965; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Articulation Committee, 1970; 5 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Biological Science, 1963-1964; 35 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Biology-Botany-Zoology, 1968; 30 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Business Administration, 1965-1970; 85 items (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Architecture, 1971; 60 items (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Continuing Education, 1969-1972; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Counseling-Education, 1964; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Economics-English, 1966; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Education-Graduate School, 1968; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Engineering-Math, 1962; 25 items (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Fine Arts-Interior Design-Architecture, 1966-1967; 35 items (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Foreign Languages-Music, 1965; 35 items (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Home Economics-Psychology, 1964, 1968; 80 items (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
    - Math-Engineering-Data Processing, 1965-1967; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Minority Studies-Forestry, 1971; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Nursing-Financial Aids, 1968; 25 items (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Office Administration-Deans, 1965; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Pharmacy-Speech-Education, 1969-1970; 60 items (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Physical Education, 1963, 1968; 55 items (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
    - Physics-Chemistry, 1963; 25 items (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Police Science-Geology, 1967; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - President's WACC Meeting, 1969-1971; 100 items (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Speech-Forestry, 1962; 25 items (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Washington Association of Community Colleges, 1967-1968; 45 items (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Education (Correspondence), 1940-1980; c.
    Consists of correspondence, studies, projects and statistics concerning all facets of education. A newsletter is also included.
    - General, 1960-1969; 100 items (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - University of Washington, 1957-1975; 40 items (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Extended Secondary Programs, 1959-1962; 25 items (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Follow-up Study for Junior Colleges and Others, 1957-1967; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - National Articulation Project, 1972-1973; 35 items (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Newsletter, 1973-1980; 7 items (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Postsecondary Education, 1972; 8 items (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Public High Schools in Washington, 1940-1942; 2 items (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Statistics, 1952-1973; 10 items (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Study on Higher Education, 1961-1966; 100 items (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Transfer Study, 1957-1965; 25 items (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Junior And Community Colleges, 1954-1977; d.
    Consists of reports, studies, workshop information, minutes, flyer materials, and correspondence.
    - Coordinating Committee Junior College-Final Report, 1954-1966; 100 items (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Follow-up Study on Junior College Workshops, 1962-1967; 15 items (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Junior College Workshops-University of Washington, 1956; 25 items (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Minutes: Committee on Academic Relations with Washington Colleges, 1962-1963; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Minutes: Washington Association of Community Colleges, 1963-1969; 8 items (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Relationship of Washington State University to the Community College-Flyer, 1961-1964; 30 items (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Washington Association of Community Colleges, 1972-1977; 200 items (Box 2, Folder 55)